#### **ALEKSEI MIKHALEV**

TEL:+44 7935475955, +79296561123 | E-MAIL: MIKHALEV.ALEKSEI1@GMAIL.COM LINKEDIN: HTTPS://WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/ALEKSMIHALEV/ GITHUB: HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/ALEKSEIMIKHALEV/DATA-SCIENCE-PROJECTS

Data analyst with strong analytical and problem-solving skills. Have a proven ability to manage projects and build effective business relationships with clients that I developed during 8 years' work experience in international law firms and venture capital funds. Working with major companies as well as startups resulted in my business acumen and understanding specifics of large and small businesses and various industries. Entrepreneurial mindset, ambitions and drive for result are my strengths in looking for a business solution. These skills coupled with the constant learning in data analytics and programming allow me to slice and dice information about business problem and find an effective solution. Completed MSc in Business Innovation from Birkbeck, University of London with Merit and ready to start working immediately.

# **AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS**

**WINNER OF CHEVENING SCHOLARSHIP 2018** 

(full-covered scholarship)

DATA ANALYTICS COURSE October 2019

IBM CERTIFICATE: DATA SCIENCE FOUNDATIONS -

LEVEL 1

LYNDA CERTIFICATE: ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE

FOUNDATIONS: THINKING MACHINES

**SECTOR SPECIFIC EVENTS ATTENDED** 

Chevening Leadership Program, one of the most prestigious

UK programs for future leaders sponsored by the UK

government

January 2019 January 2019

COGX2019, London Business Show 2018,

Big Data LDN 2018,

Digital Transformation Europe Expo 2019

#### **KEY SKILLS**

Python (Numpy, Pandas, Sklearn, Seaborn, NLP, ULMFiT); EDA; Git, Jupiter; Due Diligence, documents and reports drafting.

#### **EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS**

### BIRKBECK, UNIVERSITY OF LONDON, UK

MSc Business Innovation With Entrepreneurship And Innovation Management (2018-2019)

- Courses: Blockchain; Entrepreneurial Finance; Entrepreneurial Venture Creation; Principles of Organisation and Management, Entrepreneurship and Innovation; Innovation Systems: Network and Social Capital; Innovation: Management and Policy
- Thesis: The Role of Artificial Intelligence in Business Model of Small and Medium-sized Enterprises

# MOSCOW STATE LAW ACADEMY NAMED BY O.E. KUTAFIN, MOSCOW (RUSSIA)

LAW DEGREE WITH HONOURS (2007-2012)

- Courses: International Private Law, Modern Cross-Border Corporate Law: Takeovers and Mergers, International Commercial Arbitration, Banking Law, Civil Law, Criminal Law, IP Law, etc.
- Thesis: Enforcement Practice of LCIA

# COLLEGE OF VORONEZH STATE TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY, VORONEZH (RUSSIA)

Engineer in Telecommunication Networks and Switching Systems (2003-2007)

- Courses: Mathematics, Physics, Engineering Graphics, Electronic Engineering, Telecommunication Signals, Power Supply of Communication Devices, Discrete Messages Transmission, Multichannel Transmission Systems, Digital Switching Systems, Informatics, Fundamentals of Economics, etc.
- **Practical trainings during studies:** Radio Engineering (3 weeks), Electromechanical (5,5 weeks), Technology (4 weeks).

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### QA LOCALIZATION TESTER, PTW, LONDON, NOVEMBER 2019 - JANUARY 2020

Company provides testing and quality assurance localization services for game manufacturers

Being a part of the Russian team, I tested software (games) regarding localization for Russian market.

## VENTURE LAWYER, INTERNET-INITIATIVES DEVELOPMENT FUND, MOSCOW, APRIL 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2018

The Russian venture capital fund which invests in tech companies at early stages (pre-seed, seed), and series A; and provide startups and key players in the venture industry with educational and expert support. The fund invested in more than 400 companies.

• Was responsible for venture deals structuring (from term sheets negotiation to deal closing), advising founders re legal issues, conducting due diligence, and ongoing communication with investment managers and founders;

• Structured and closed more than 20 venture deals and advised more than 30 start-ups on various issues. Three start-ups became unicorns and successfully entered the foreign market and raised further investment rounds.

#### SOLE LEGAL COUNSEL, UCF INVESTMENT COMPANY, MOSCOW, MARCH 2015 - APRIL 2016

Venture capital fund focused on "media-for-equity" investments

- Successfully managed day-to-day activities related to legal issues such as: deal structuring, advising beneficiaries about legal risks, doing legal researches; communication with company's counterparts, negotiating contracts;
- Negotiated and structured contracts with one of the biggest Russian media agency and medium-sized businesses in order to implement new investment model "media for equity" to the Russian market.

### LAWYER (CORPORATE PRACTICE), CAPITAL LEGAL SERVICES, MOSCOW, AUGUST 2014 - MARCH 2015

Russian law firm with offices in Moscow, Saint-Petersburg and Helsinki.

- Effectively managed projects of corporate practice and day-to-day communication with clients;
- Executed a significant part of the restructuring plan of the big company and managed the process of its share issuance;
- Closed several major M&A deals, one of them was the business acquisition in 47 jurisdictions.
- Successfully trained and managed paralegals.

### PARALEGAL, CLEARY GOTTLIEB STEEN & HAMILTON, MOSCOW, FEBRUARY 2011 - MARCH 2014

Top-tier global international law firm

- Revealed a significant risk conducting due diligence of one of the biggest clients for its upcoming SPO, successfully
  discussed the risk with senior partners and client's lawyers. As a result, the risk was mitigated and disclosed in the
  prospectus for the London stock exchange;
- Being a paralegal successfully conducted due diligence for SPO procedures of Sberbank, the biggest bank in Russia, and IPO of Promsvyazbank, the leading Russian bank;
- Dramatically developed analytical skills and attention to details doing due diligences of the biggest Russian companies
  from various industries, as well as business acumen. Drafting documents, reports and doing daily correspondence in
  Russian and English developed business writing, communication and negotiation skills, and learnt best international clientfocused practices.

# LEGAL ASSISTANT, GRAIN COMPANY RAZGULAY (RAZGULAY GROUP), MOSCOW, FEBRUARY 2010 – FEBRUARY 2011

Major grain producer in Russia

As a junior legal assistant worked part-time and developed my skills in legal research and legal drafting; learnt corporate
governance on practice by drafting internal documents for the board of directors' meetings and general shareholders
meetings.

# **EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

#### WINNER AT "PIONEER AWARDS 2019" IN BEST BUSINESS PITCH NOMINATION

- Participated with the team in Pioneer Competition Birkbeck extra-curriculum program for young enthusiastic entrepreneurs who are focused on developing key business skills and creating new disruptive ventures;
- Created from scratch two different business ideas and both got shortlisted for final; pitched them to the panel of experts from venture capital funds, business consulting firms and founders of successful companies, and won.

### **MSAL DEBATE CLUB MEMBER, 2008-2010**

- Had been an active member of the debating club and participated in more than 10 internal and external British Parliamentary Debating;
- Participated as a judge at internal debating sessions and coached less experienced debaters.

#### **HOBBIES**

- Muay-Thai, swimming, music hedonism, reading books with original ideas, and habits creation;
- Learning about machine learning algorithms and its implementation in real business cases.
- Participating in Kaggle competitions